Guide to the James Omura personal archive M2294
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series 7. Audio-Visual Materials, 1920-1995
  - Subseries 7.1. Photographs
    - Photograph photocopies (Box 29, Folder 25)
    - Resisters and Frank Chin (Box 29, Folder 26)
    - Tamesa, Uhachi (Box 29, Folder 27)
    - Wedding portrait (Box 29, Folder 28)
    - Weglyn, Michi (Box 29, Folder 29)
    - Unidentified photos (Box 29, Folder 30)
    - 3 photograph albums and 1 oversized group photo (Flat-box 63)
  - Subseries 7.2. Audio Cassettes
    - 82 cassette tapes (Flat-box 66, Cassette 1-35, Flat-box 67, Flat-box 68, Cassette 1-13)
      Existence and Location of Copies
      Cassettes have been digitized.
  - Subseries 7.3. Video Recordings
    - 3 videocassettes (Flat-box 68, Videotape 14-16)
  - Subseries 7.4. Computer Disks
- Series 8. Ephemera & Memorabilia, 1930-1994
  - Address lists & notes, including the Argonaut Publishing Co. (Box 30, Folder 1-2)
  - American Kennel Club (A.K.C.) Registration & Pedigree, 1945 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Banner – “Nisei America, Know the Facts” (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Appointment cards, b9ook order, book plate, bowling patches and scores (Box 30, Folder 5-9)
  - Brochures – U.S. Army Military Institute (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Business cards, calendar, Commencement Program – Broadway High School (Box 30, Folder 11-14)
  - Conference badges, programs (Box 30, Folder 15-18)
  - Credit cards; telephone guide – Metropolitan Denver, Japanese American; drawings (Box 30, Folder 19-22)
  - Envelopes – Pacific Coast Evacuee Placement Bureau (Box 30, Folder 23-24)
  - Envelopes - used (Box 30, Folder 25)
  - Flyers - various (Box 30, Folder 26-30)
  - Handwriting analysis results (Box 30, Folder 31)
  - Immigration card (Box 30, Folder 32)
  - Invitations (Box 30, Folder 33-34)
  - Letterheads (Box 30, Folder 35)
  - Linotype – column masthead “Know the Facts” (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Maps – earthquake faults; research libraries (Box 31, Folder 2-3)
  - Medical receipts; membership cards; Memorial Service Programs; Menu – Kimochi Nutrition Program (Box 31, Folder 4-7)
  - Press passes; quotations (Box 31, Folder 8-9)
  - Report cards; ribbons; school letter & pins; sports scores; tax chart (Box 31, Folder 10-14)
- Series 9. Research Materials, 1930-1994
  - Bibliography – Seattle Public Library, 1971 (Box 31, Folder 15)
  - Bibliography – University of California, Berkeley Library, 1982-1983 (Box 31, Folder 16)
  - Biographical Information – Kramer, Fay (Box 31, Folder 17)
  - Catalogs (Box 31, Folder 18)
  - Certificate of Authenticity (Box 31, Folder 19)
  - Conferences – Japanese America: Contemporary Perspectives on Internment, 1980 (Box 31, Folder 20)
  - Conferences – Relocation and Redress: The Japanese American Experience, 1983 (Box 31, Folder 21)
  - Conferences – Views from Within: The Japanese American Wartime Internment Experience, 1987 (Box 31, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, 1921, [n.d.] (Box 31, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence, 1941-1945 (Box 31, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence, 1949 (Box 31, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence, 1964-1965 (Box 31, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence, 1980-1988 (Box 31, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence, 1993 (Box 31, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence course, fingerprinting [1946] (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - F.B.I. files, 1940 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - F.B.I. files, 1941-1942 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - F.B.I. files, 1943-01-1943-03 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - F.B.I. files, 1943-04-1943-11 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - F.B.I. files, 1944 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - F.B.I. files, 1945 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - F.B.I. files, 1946 (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - F.B.I. files, 1984 (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - F.B.I. files, Fair Play Committee [1944] (Box 32, Folder 10, Box 33, Folder 1-2)
  - F.B.I. files, Fair Play Committee, 1945-1946 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - F.B.I. files – Information Requests (Box 33, Folder 4-5)
  - F.B.I. files – Joseph F. Kurihara, 1942-1943 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - F.B.I. files – Rocky Nippon, 1942-1945 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - F.B.I. files – Rocky Shimpo, 1942-1945 (Box 34, Folder 1-2)
  - F.B.I. Files – Shiro Toda, 1943-1946 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Finding aids, 1985 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Fragments (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Government Documents, 1941-1944 (Box 34, Folder 6-9)
  - Government Documents, 1983, 1987 (Box 34, Folder 10-11)
  - Government Documents – Bibliography on War Relocation, Japanese and Japanese Americans (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - Government Documents – Civil Liberties Act of 1988 Voluntary Information Form (Box 34, Folder 13)
  - Government Documents – Commission on Wartime Relocation and Internment of Civilians, 1981 (Box 34, Folder 14)
  - Government Documents – Committee on Un-American Activities, 1943 (Box 34, Folder 15)
  - Government Documents – Community Analysis – Heart Mountain Relocation Center, 1944 (Box 34, Folder 16)
  - Government Documents – Congressional Record, 1942 (Box 34, Folder 17)
  - Government Documents – Department of Justice, 1942 (Box 34, Folder 19)
  - Government Documents – Department of the Navy, 1942-1945, 1984-1987 (Box 34, Folder 19)
  - Government Documents – Department of State, 1944, 1980, 1986 (Box 34, Folder 20)
  - Government Documents – Diagram of the United States Senate, 1935 (Box 34, Folder 21)
  - Government Documents – Harbor Defenses of Los Angeles, 1944 (Box 34, Folder 22)
  - Government Documents – House of Representatives – H.R. 8163, 1935 (Box 34, Folder 23)
  - Government Documents, 1942 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Government Documents – House of Representatives – H. Res. 282, 1943 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Government Documents – House of Representatives – H.R. 3566 and H.R. 3999, 1947 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Government Documents – House of Representatives – H.R. 5977, 1979 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Government Documents – House of Representatives – H.R. 4110, 1984 (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Government Documents - House of Representatives – H.R. 442, 1987 (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Government Documents – Human Rights Provisions Adopted by Denver Charter Convention, 1947 (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - Government Documents – Library of Congress, Copyright Office, 1939 (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Government Documents – National Archives, 1986-1987 (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - Government Documents – National Archives Government Documents – Office of War Information, 1944, 1967 (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - Government Documents – Public Law 96-317, Public Law 97-152 (Box 35, Folder 11-12)
  - Government Documents – Selective Service Bulletin, 1940 (Box 35, Folder 13)
  - Government Documents – Selective Service Violators, 1944-1945 (Box 35, Folder 14)
  - Government Documents – Senate – S. Res. 299, 1942 (Box 35, Folder 15)
  - Government Documents – Senate – S. 444, 1943 (Box 35, Folder 16)
  - Government Documents – Senate – Bill S. 1009, 1987 (Box 35, Folder 17)
  - Government Documents – State of Colorado – House Concurrent Resolutions No. 1, 2, 3 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Government Documents – United States Department of Commerce, 1988 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Government Documents – War Relocation Authority (WRA), 1942-1945 (Box 36, Folder 3-4)
  - Interviews – Karl R. Bendetsen (Colonel), 1942, 1972, 1984 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Interviews – Art Emi, Frank Emi, Grant Emi & Eric Emi, 1982 (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Interviews – Art Emi, Frank Emi, Grant Emi & Eric Emi Interviews – Frank Emi, 1982 (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Interviews – Frank Emi & Glen Hayashi, 1982 (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Interviews – Shirley Castelnuovo, Shigeo Hamai, Merry Omori, and Harold Tsunehara, 1986 (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - Interviews – Gordon Hirabayashi & James Hirabayashi, 1984 (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - Interviews – Isamu Horino, 1944 (Box 36, Folder 11)
  - Interviews – William Hosakawa, 1973 (Box 36, Folder 12)
  - Interviews – John B. Hughes, 1943 (Box 36, Folder 13)
  - Interviews – Masao Kataoka, 1985 (Box 36, Folder 14)
  - Interviews – Masao Kataoka, 1984 (Box 36, Folder 15)
  - Interviews – John Kitasako, 1984 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Interviews – Guntaro & Gloria Kubota and Grace Kubota Ybarra, 1983 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Interviews – George Maruyama & Isamu Kuse, 1986 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Interviews – Mike Masaoka, 1981 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Interviews – George Matsumonji, 1985 (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Interviews – Cedric Shimo, 1985 (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Interviews – Uhachi & Kay Tamesa, 1982 (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Interviews – Seichi Yasutake, 1943 (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - Interviews – Grace Kubota Ybarra and Gloria Tsusiko Kubota, 1984 (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - Legal Documents – Affidavit – Burling, John L, 1947 (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - Legal Documents – Appellant’s Reply Brief – Shigeru Fujii vs. United States of America (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - Legal Documents – Army Board for Correction of Military Records – Shigeo Hamai, et al., 1982 (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - Legal Documents – Brief – John T. Regan vs. Cameron King, as Registrar of Voters in the City and County of San Francisco, State of California, 1943 (Box 37, Folder 13)
  - Legal Documents – Brief in Support of Application for Secretarial Review of Punitive Discharge Pursuant to 10 U.S.C. Sec. 874 (b) – Application of: Taniguchi,Kataoka, Sumoge, Ogawa, Tsunehara, Morita, Hamai, Hayakawa,, Nozawa, Okamoto, Nomiyama, 1980 (Box 37, Folder 14)
  - Legal Documents – Brief of Appellants – Reply Brief of Appellants – Ki Yosha Okamoto vs. United States of America, 1945 (Box 37, Folder 15)
  - Legal Documents – Brief of Appellee – Kiyoshi Okamoto, et al vs. United States of America (Box 37, Folder 16)
  - Legal Documents – Brief of Wayne M. Collins as Amicus Curiae on Behalf of the American Civil Liberties Union (Box 37, Folder 17)
  - Legal Documents – Complaint of Monetary and Declaratory Relief for Violation of Plaintiffs’ Constitutional Rights... – William Hohri, et al vs. The United States of Americai, 1985-1986 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Legal Documents – District Court of the United States, District of Wyoming Grand Jury Indictment, 1944 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Legal Documents – Exhibits – Kataoka, Ogawa, Morita, Okamoto, Nomiyama, Hayakawa, 1944 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Legal Documents – General Court Martial – Kataoka, Masao, 1944-1987 (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Legal Documents – General Court Martial – Nozawa, Hakubun (NMI), 1944 (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Legal Documents – Memorandum on Motion to Quash and Demurrer to Indictment - United States of America vs. Kiyoshi Okamoto, et al., 1944 (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Legal Documents – Memorandum on Motion to Quash and Demurrer to Indictment - United States of America vs. Kiyoshi Okamoto, et al., 1944 (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Legal Documents – On Writ of Certiorari to the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit – United States of America vs. William Hohri, et al., 1986 (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Legal Documents – Opinion by Tenth Circuit Court of Appeals in Heart Mountain Conspiracy Case, 1945 (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - Legal Documents – Petition - Alien Enemies, 1945 (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - Legal Documents – Petition for Rehearing and Suggestion for Rehearing En Blanc – William Hohri, et al vs. United States of America (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - Legal Documents – Petition for Writ of Certiorari/Petitioner’s Reply Brief on Petition for Writ of Certiorari – Minola Tamesa vs. United States of America, 1944 (Box 38, Folder 12)
  - United States Circuit Court of Appeals for the Tenth Circuit and Brief in Support Thereof – Okamoto, Nakadate, Wakaye, Emi, Tamesa, Horino, and Kubota vs. United States of America, 1945 (Box 38, Folder 13)
  - Legal Documents – Petitioner’s Reply Brief – Gordon K. Hirabayashi vs. United States of America, 1985 (Box 38, Folder 14)
  - Legal Documents – Plaintiffs’ Brief on Their Motion for Summary Judgment and for Judgment on the Pleadings and to Strike Defendants’ Pleadings, 1952 (Box 38, Folder 15)
  - Legal Documents – Transcript of Proceedings – William Hohri, et al vs. United States of America, 1985 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Legal Documents – Trial Brief – United States of America vs. Tsuruko Wallace, Florence Shivze, and Billie Shitara Tanigoshi (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Legal Documents – United States Circuit Court of Appeals – Kiyoshi Okamoto, et al vs. United States of America, 1945 (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Legal Documents – United States District Court Western District of Washington – Gordon K. Hirabayaski vs. United States of America, 1986 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Legal Documents – United States of America vs. Minoru Yasui, 1942 (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Legal Documents – War Relocation Agency Hearing – Frank Emi, 1944 (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Maps – Denver, Colorado, 1955 (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - Maps – Seattle, Washington – Old Japanese District (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - Narrator’s Gift to Interviewer, 1985 (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - Newsletters – Asian American Journalists Association (A.A.J.A.), 1987-1988 (Box 39, Folder 10)
  - Newsletters- ALCA Action Letter (Associated Landscape Contractors of America, Inc.), 1966 (Box 39, Folder 11)
  - Newsletters – American Committee for the Kagawa Centennial Project, 1986 (Box 39, Folder 12)
  - Newsletters – Asian American Network, 1988 (Box 39, Folder 13)
  - Newsletters – Asian Comparative Collection, 1988 (Box 39, Folder 14)
  - Newsletters – Asian Ministries News Section, 1981 (Box 39, Folder 15)
  - Newsletters – Book News, 1984 (Box 39, Folder 16)
  - Newsletters – Crosscurrents, 1992 (Box 39, Folder 17)
  - Newsletters – Eyes & Ears, 1992 (Box 39, Folder 18)
  - Newsletters – JACL Legacy Fund, 1991 (Box 39, Folder 19)
  - Newsletters – Japanese (Box 39, Folder 20)
  - Newsletters – The Japanese American Library Bulletin, 1986-1992 (Box 39, Folder 21)
  - Newsletters – NCRR (Box 39, Folder 22)
  - Newsletters – National Council for Japanese American Redress, 1986-1989 (Box 39, Folder 23)
  - Newsletters – News & Views, 1944 (Box 39, Folder 24)
  - Newsletters – Nikkei Review, 1989 (Box 39, Folder 25)
  - Newsletters – OTR, 1989 (Box 39, Folder 26)
  - Newsletters – Outlook, 1988 (Box 39, Folder 27)
  - Newsletters – P.A.C.T.S. (Pacific & Asian American Center for Theology & Strategies), 1982 (Box 39, Folder 28)
  - Newsletters – Redress Committee Salinas Valley JACL, 1985 (Box 39, Folder 29)
  - Organizations – American Civil Liberties Union (ACLU), 1945-1947 (Box 39, Folder 30)
  - Organizations – Alliance Working for Asian Rights and Empowerment (AWARE) (Box 39, Folder 31)
  - Organizations – American Council of the Institute of Pacific Relations, 1941, 1944 (Box 39, Folder 32)
  - Organizations – American Council on Public Affairs (Box 39, Folder 33)
  - Organizations – American Friends Service Committee (Box 39, Folder 34)
  - Organizations – California Historical Society Library (Box 39, Folder 35)
  - Organizations – Civil Liberties League (Box 39, Folder 36)
  - Organizations – Commission on Wartime Relocation & Internment of Civilians, 1981 (Box 39, Folder 37)
  - Organizations – Fair Play Committee, 1993 (Box 39, Folder 38)
  - Organizations – Fellowship of Reconciliation (Box 39, Folder 39)
  - Organizations – Hollywood Japanese Cultural Institute, 1994 (Box 39, Folder 40)
  - Organizations – Japanese American Citizens League (JACL) (Box 40, Folder 1-5)
  - Organizations – Japanese American Citizens League (JACL) – Anti-Axis Committee (Box 40, Folder 6-7)
  - Organizations – Japanese American Citizens League (JACL) – Partial Manuscript (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - Organizations – Japanese American Citizens League (JACL) – Projects (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - Organizations – Kyokuto Kenkyu Kai (Far East Research Institute), 1945 (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - Organizations – National Coalition for Redress/Reparations (NCRR) (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - Organizations – National Council for Japanese American Redress (NCJAR), 1980-1988 (Box 40, Folder 12)
  - Photocopying Requests, 1983-1985 (Box 40, Folder 13)
  - Poems (Box 40, Folder 14)
  - Poems - Inada, Lawson, 1983 (Box 40, Folder 15)
  - Poems – Japanese Americans, 1915-1947 (Box 40, Folder 16)
  - Poems - Today’s Poetry, 1923 (Box 40, Folder 17)
  - Press Releases, 1943-1947 (Box 40, Folder 18)
  - Publications – ABI Digest, Amerasia Journal, 1989, 1982 (Box 40, Folder 19-20)
  - Publications – Americans of Japanese Ancestry and the United States Constitution 1787 – 1987 (Box 40, Folder 21)
  - Publications – “An Analysis of the Proposed Constitutional Amendments and Initiative Law”, 1944 (Box 40, Folder 22)
  - Publications – An Open Letter to the Honorable S. I. Hayakawa from Japanese America, 1979 (Box 40, Folder 23)
  - Publications in alphabetical order, mostly single issues or a few issues (Box 41, Folder 1-16)
  - Publications in alphabetical order, beginning with "Japanese American" (Box 41, Folder 17-24)
  - Publications in alphabetical order, mostly single issues or a few issues (Box 42, Folder 1-24)
  - Relocation Center Materials – Granada, Colorado (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Relocation Center Materials – Guide to the Japanese-American Relocation Centers Records, 1935 – 1953, 1981 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Relocation Center Materials – Heart Mountain, Wyoming, 1943-1945 (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Relocation Center Materials – Manzanar, California, 1942 (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Relocation Center Materials – Minidoka, Idaho, 1942-1943 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Relocation Center Materials – Poston, Arizona, 1942-1944 (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Relocation Center Materials – Rohwer, Arkansas (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - Relocation Center Materials – Topaz, Utah, 1942 – 1944, 1962, 1983 (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - Relocation Center Materials – Tule Lake, California, 1944 (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - Scripts – “The Heart Mountain Draft Resistance: The Boys of Mountain View – San Jose”, 1992 (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - Scripts – “The Hopeless Case of Father (Box 43, Folder 11)
  - Scripts – “The Lim Report, A Dramatic Reading”, 1993 (Box 43, Folder 12)
  - Scripts – “The Lim Report, A Dramatic Reading” Scripts – “The Lim Report: A Question of Who We Are”, 1993 (Box 43, Folder 13)
  - Scripts – “The Lim Report, A Dramatic Reading”, 1993 (Box 43, Folder 14)
  - Scripts – “A Study of the Cultural Aspects of the Nisei Co-Ed” (Box 43, Folder 15)
  - Sheet music - photocopy (Box 43, Folder 16)
  - Speeches – Bendetsen, Karl R. (Colonel), 1942 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Speeches – Castelnuovo, Shirley (Dr.), 1986-1987 (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Speeches – Coombs, F. Alan, 1983 (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Speeches – Daniels, Roger, 1970 (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Speeches – Deutsch, Monroe E. (Dr.), 1942 (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Speeches – Emi, Frank, 1982, 1990, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Speeches – Gaeth, Arthur, 1944 (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Speeches – Hansen, Arthur A., 1989 (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Speeches – Hohri, William, 1991 (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - Speeches – Hosokawa, William, 1973, 1983, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - Speeches – Inouye, Daniel K. (Senator), 1979 (Box 44, Folder 11)
  - Speeches – Kawai, ? (Box 44, Folder 12)
  - Speeches – Kuroki, Ben (Sergeant), 1944 (Box 44, Folder 13)
  - Speeches – Masaoka, Mike, 1982 (Box 44, Folder 14)
  - Speeches – McWilliams, Carey, 1949 (Box 44, Folder 15)
  - Speeches – Myer, Dillon S., 1944 (Box 44, Folder 16)
  - Speeches – Nakano, Bert, 1988 (Box 44, Folder 17)
  - Speeches – Shimo, Cedrick, 1988-1989 (Box 44, Folder 18)
  - Speeches – Smith, Charles Z., 1974 (Box 44, Folder 19)
  - Speeches – Suzuki, Peter T., 1981 (Box 44, Folder 20)
  - Speeches – Washburne, Claude D. (Lt. Col.), 1944 (Box 44, Folder 21)
  - Speeches – Yasui, Minoru, 1983 (Box 44, Folder 22)
  - Statements – Abe, Paul Yozo & Slocum, Tokutaro, 1943 (Box 44, Folder 23)
  - Statements – Bendetsen, Karl R, 1981 (Box 44, Folder 24)
  - Statements – Collins, Wayne M.,1958, 1968 (Box 44, Folder 25)
  - Statements – Eisenhower, Milton S., 1981 (Box 44, Folder 26)
  - Statements – Ennis, Edward J., 1984 (Box 44, Folder 27)
  - Statements – Kiku Hori, 1981 (Box 44, Folder 28)
  - Statements – Herzig, John A., 1984 (Box 44, Folder 29)
  - Statements – Hohri, William M., 1986 (Box 44, Folder 30)
  - Statements – Irons, Peter H., 1981-1983 (Box 44, Folder 31)
  - Statements – Kanazawa, Joe (Mr. And Mrs.), 1943 (Box 44, Folder 32)
  - Statements – Kataoka, Mas, 1982 (Box 44, Folder 33)
  - Statements – Lowman, David D., 1984 (Box 44, Folder 34)
  - Statements – McCloy, John J., 1981 (Box 44, Folder 35)
  - Statements – Masaoka, Mike, 1943, 1986 (Box 44, Folder 36)
  - Statements – Myer, Dillon S., 1943 (Box 44, Folder 37)
  - Statements – Okamura, B. Taeko Sakai, 1981 (Box 44, Folder 38)
  - Statements – Okamura, Raymond, 1981 (Box 44, Folder 39)
  - Statements – Rauh, Joseph L., Jr., 1982 (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Statements – Robinson, William L., 1986 (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Statements – Sasaki, Shosuke, 1980 (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Statements – Tono, Jack, 1981, 1986 (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Statements – Tsuneishi, Satoru, 1981 (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Statements – Wiener, Frederick Bernays, 1984 (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Transcripts – ABC News 20/20, 1991 (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Authors Unidentified, 1943-1982 (Box 45, Folder 8-11)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Abe, Frank, 1990, 1992, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 12)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Arrington, Leonard J., 1962 (Box 45, Folder 13)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Barnhart, Edward N., 1962 (Box 45, Folder 14)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Biddle, Francis Beverly (Box 45, Folder 15)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Bittner, Eric, 1991 (Box 45, Folder 16)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Bratzel, John F. & Rout, Leslie B. Jr., 1982 (Box 45, Folder 17)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Brinkley, Alan, 1983 (Box 45, Folder 18)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Cary, Otis, 1975 (Box 45, Folder 19)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Castelnuovo, Shirley, 1987-1990 (Box 45, Folder 20)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Cates, Rita Takahashi, 1980 (Box 45, Folder 21)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Chandler, Arthur (Editor), 1979 (Box 45, Folder 22)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Chin, Frank, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 23-26)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Chin, Frank, 1981-1991 (Box 46, Folder 1-8)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Chin, Steven, 1993 (Box 46, Folder 9)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Clark, Paul F (Box 46, Folder 10)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Colborn, Fern M., 1946 (Box 46, Folder 11)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Comager, Henry Steele, 1954 (Box 46, Folder 12)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Culley, John, 1982 (Box 46, Folder 13)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Daniels, Roger, 1981 (Box 46, Folder 14)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – DeYoung, John, 1943 (Box 46, Folder 15)
  - Writings & Manuscripts –Writings & Manuscripts – Drinnon, Richard, 1981 (Box 46, Folder 16-18)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Drinnon, Richard, 1981 (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Drinnon, Richard, 1981-1987 (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Dunne, Gerald T., 1975 (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Eddy, Don, 1942 (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Ehrlich, Gretel (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Farago, Ladislas (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Gottlieb, Roger S., 1983 (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Halter, Jon C. Zaqw (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Hansen, Arthur A. & Hacker, David A., 1974 (Box 47, Folder 9)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Hansen, Arthur A. (Box 47, Folder 10)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Herzig, John A, 1984 (Box 47, Folder 11)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Higham, John (Editor), 1978 (Box 47, Folder 12)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Honda, Harry K., 1985, 1991 (Box 47, Folder 13)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Ichioka, Yuji, 1971 (Box 47, Folder 14)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Ikuta, Cynthia (Box 47, Folder 15)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Japanese Vernacular (Box 47, Folder 16)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Katcher, Leo, 1967 (Box 47, Folder 17)
  - Writings & Manuscripts – Kessler, Lauren, 1988 (Box 47, Folder 18)